A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Grant Funded Materials FA1839
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant File Attachments - Publications and Reports, 1955-2018; 5; 23.46 Cubic Feet
  - Yayasan Masyarakat Mandiri Film Indonesia PA 10301243 In-Docs Addendum, 2004 October (Box 61, Folder 333)
    Ford Program Officer(s): Yampolsky, Philip; Arbuckle, Heidi L.
  - Center for Justice and International Law PA 09801694, 2001 (Box 61, Folder 334, Box 62, Folder 335)
    Grantee: Center for Justice and International Law
    Grant Dates: 1998 July 01-2010 November 30
    Grant Number: 09801694
    Grant Purpose: Support for efforts to strengthen the Inter-American System for protecting human rights
    Ford Program Officer(s): Cox, Larry; Abreg, Martn; Brown, Kimberli R.; Dora, Denise Dourado; Toni, Ana; Jenkins, Alan; Farias Campero, Pablo; Bronfman, Mario; TBS/International Human Rights; Agero, Felipe; Zard, Monette
  - 21st Century School Fund PA 10200952 - Building Educational Success Together (BEST), 2001-2006 (Box 62, Folder 336-337, Box 63, Folder 338)
    Grantee: 21st Century School Fund
    Grant Dates: 2002 March 01-2009 February 28
    Grant Number: 10200952
    Grant Purpose: General support for Building Educational Success Together (BEST), a collaboration to improve public school facilities in low-income urban communities
    Grant Amount: $3,750,000.00; $3,750,000.00
  - Welfare Foundation for the Elderly Fundacin Bienestar del Adulto Mayor PA 10550666, 2006 (Box 63, Folder 339)
    Grantee: Welfare Foundation for the Elderly
    Grant Dates: 2005 March 01-2006 February 28
    Grant Number: 10550666
    Grant Purpose: To promote nondiscriminatory practices toward the elderly in urban and semi-rural communities
    Grant Amount: $30,000.00; $30,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Eguizabal, Cristina
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law PA 09800950, 1996-2001 (Box 63, Folder 340, Box 64, Folder 341)
    Grantee: Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law
    Grant Dates: 1998 March 01-2010 December 31
    Grant Number: 09800950
    Grant Purpose: Support and affirmative action-related funding for civil rights litigation and advocacy organization
    Grant Amount: $6,695,000.00; $6,695,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Jenkins, Alan; Berrien, Jacqueline; Rios, Sara; Cox, Todd; DePass, Michelle
  - Harvard University PA 09901535 - Public Sector Labor Management Cooperation, 2004 (Box 64, Folder 342)
    Grant Dates: 1999 September 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 09901535
    Grant Purpose: Support for a new program on public sector labor-management relations to disseminate and further refine models of labor-management cooperation in the public sector
    Grant Amount: $370,000.00; $370,000.00
  - Environmental Legal Assistance Center PA 09701954 - Stopping the Gray Harvest: The Global Cement Case in Sibonga, 2001 (Box 64, Folder 343)
    Grantee: Environmental Legal Assistance Center, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 1997 October 01-2006 March 31
    Grant Number: 09701954
    Grant Purpose: Support for capability building on development planning and environmental protection
    Grant Amount: $1,056,000.00; $1,056,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Hawes, Gary A.; Siskel, Suzanne E.
  - University of Michigan, Dearborn PA 10650365, 2006 (Box 64, Folder 344)
    Grantee: The Regents of the University of Michigan, Dearborn
    Grant Dates: 2006 March 01-2008 February 29
    Grant Number: 10650365
    Grant Purpose: For faculty and curriculum development to help students understand and articulate diverse perspectives on racial, religious, political and cultural issues and community forums on related themes
    Ford Program Officer(s): Balan, Jorge
  - The Aspen Institute PA 11000361, 2009 (Box 64, Folder 345)
  - Ford Foundation PA 11000888, 2011 (Box 64, Folder 346)
  - Ford Foundation PA 11000888, 2011; DVD-R (Box 64)
  - The Aspen Institute PA 10202022, 2009 (Box 64, Folder 347)
    Grant Dates: 2002 December 01-2010 February 28
    Grant Number: 10202022
    Grant Purpose: Start-up support for a new initiative on financial security dedicated to closing America's wealth gap through the creation of a new generation of publicly subsidized individual development accounts
    Grant Amount: $5,200,000.00; $5,200,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Campbell, Elizabeth C.; DeGiovanni, Frank F.; Kijakazi, Kilolo
  - Good Jobs First PA 10400295, 2005 (Box 64, Folder 348)
    Grantee: Good Jobs First
    Grant Dates: 2004 January 01-2011 May 31
    Grant Number: 10400295
    Grant Purpose: Anthony, Carl; McFate, Katherine; McGahey, Richard; Chen, Donald D.T.
    Grant Amount: $1,225,000.00; $1,225,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): For research, education and outreach to build a constituency for Smart Growth practices within organized labor
  - Legal Services for Children, Inc PA 10650404, 2006 (Box 64, Folder 349)
    Grantee: Legal Services for Children, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2006 January 01-2006 December 31
    Grant Number: 10650404
    Grant Purpose: For the bilingual outreach initiative to provide services to disadvantaged children with disabilities in non English speaking communities
    Grant Amount: $20,000.00; $20,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Smith, Theresa
  - University of Wisconsin-Madison PA 10600401, 2006 (Box 64, Folder 350)
    Grantee: University of Wisconsin-Madison
    Grant Dates: 2006 February 01-2009 July 31
    Grant Number: 10600401
    Grant Purpose: To collaborate with three Vietnamese centers of economic research to assess the links among rapid growth, resource depletion and poverty in Vietnam and recommend policy responses
    Grant Amount: $430,000.00; $430,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Bailey, Charles R.
  - FinMark Trust PA 10650201, 2005 (Box 64, Folder 351)
    Grantee: Finmark Trust
    Grant Number: 10650201
    Grant Purpose: For research on the rural outreach of banking services in South Africa and Botswana
  - The Journal of Educational Sociology - The Expanding Role of Television in American Education, John J. Scanlon, 1959 May (Box 64, Folder 352)
  - Regents of the University of Michigan PA 06900724 - Hierarchy in Organizations: A Cross National Comparison, A.S. Tannenbaum et. al., 1969 (Box 64, Folder 353, Box 65, Folder 354)
    Grant Dates: 1969 October 01-1972 September 30
    Grant Number: 06900724
    Grant Purpose: Three comparative studies on the social psychological aspects of organization in East Europe and the United States
    Ford Program Officer(s): Gaer, Felice D.
  - Vanderbilt University (06100379) - Staff Study No. 1: Utilization of Instructional Space at George Peabody College for Teachers and Vanderbilt University, 1961 (Box 65, Folder 355)
  - International Institute Of Communications Ltd. (07200350) - The Role of Broadcasting in National Development, Elihu Katz and E.G. Wedell, 1975 (Box 65, Folder 356)
    Grantee: International Institute Of Communications Ltd.
    Grant Dates: 1972 October 01-1976 September 30
    Grant Number: 07200350
    Grant Purpose: Study of the role of broadcasting in national development
    Grant Amount: $118,500.00; $118,401.26
    Ford Program Officer(s): Silj, Alessandro
  - Trustees of Boston University (07000302) - Afro-American Studies Program, Occasional Paper Number Two, Black Images in Films, Stereotyping, and Self-Perception as Viewed by Black Actresses, 1975 (Box 65, Folder 357)
    Grant Purpose: Support for a graduate program in afro american studies
  - Trustees of Boston University (07000302) - Afro-American Studies Program, Occasional Paper Number Three, Criminology and the Criminal Justice System: Old and New, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 358)
  - Trustees of Boston University (07000302) Afro-American Studies Program, Occasional Paper Number Five, Proceedings of a Symposium on The African Dispersal: Expectations and Realities, 1976 April 24 (Box 66, Folder 359)
  - International Council For Educational Development Ewa/cee (07200351) - An International Perspective: The University's Response to Societal Demands, Edited by Philip G. Altbach, 1975 February (Box 66, Folder 360)
    Grantee: International Council For Educational Development Ewa/cee
    Grant Dates: 1972 August 11-1977 September 30
    Grant Number: 07200351
    Ford Program Officer(s): Barber, Elinor G.
  - The Regents of the University of California, Berkeley (07300018) - Rethinking Childhood: Perspectives on Development and Society, Edited by Arlene Skolnick, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 361)
    Grantee: The Regents of the University of California, Berkeley
    Grant Dates: 1972 July 01-1981 September 30
    Grant Number: 07300018
    Grant Purpose: Partial support of research and publications of the childhood and government project
    Grant Amount: $2,415,244.00; $2,415,244.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Meade, Edward J.
  - National Council On Employment Policy (07100158) - Comparative Labor Market Policies of Japan, West Germany, United Kingdom, France, Australia, Conference Proceedings of The National Council on Employment Policy, Edited by Howard Rosen, 1985 April 25 (Box 66, Folder 362)
    Grantee: National Council On Employment Policy
    Grant Dates: 1971 February 01-1990 June 30
    Grant Number: 07100158
    Grant Purpose: Support of the center for policy studies for evaluations of national social policies and programs
    Grant Amount: $1,141,943.00; $1,141,943.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Lanigan, John
  - Educational Policy Center, Inc. (07200239) - A Late Start Toward Equal Opportunity: The Experience of Blacks on Predominately White Campuses, 1972-1973 by William M. Boyd, II, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 363)
    Grantee: Educational Policy Center, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 1972 June 01-1973 February 28
    Grant Number: 07200239
    Grant Purpose: Survey of the problems of black students in predominantly white colleges
    Grant Amount: $85,150.00; $85,150.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Payton, Benjamin Franklin
  - University of Miami (07100132) - Interstate 75: Evaluation of Corridors Proposed for South Florida, Environmental Study Panel Report, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 364)
    Grantee: University of Miami
    Grant Dates: 1971 January 01-1973 June 30
    Grant Number: 07100132
    Grant Purpose: Applied Research and Analysis of Environmental Problems in South Florida Available to Other Agencies Managing the Area's Resources and Development
    Grant Amount: $240,000.00; $240,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Ames, Edward A.
  - George Washington University (07100143) - The Ford Fellows in Educational Journalism Report, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 365)
    Desegregation
    Magnet Schools
    School Finance
    Competency Based Testing
    Back to Basics
    Special Education
    Textbook Selection
    Parenbt Power in Education
    Educational Testing
    Grant Dates: 1970 September 01-1981 December 31
    Grant Number: 07100143
    Grant Purpose: Continuing support for the activities of the institute for educational leadership (iel)
    Grant Amount: $6,692,600.00; $6,692,600.00
  - George Washington University (07100143); The Institute for Educational Leadership, Incorporated (08100684) - The Ford Fellows in Educational Journalism Report, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 366)
    Education of the Gifted and Talente
    Minimum Competency Testing
    Parent Participation in the Schoold
    Education and the Tax Revolt
    America's Black Colleges
    Achieving Quality Education
    Declining Enrollments and School Closings
    School Finance in the South
    Indian Education
- Gender, Racial, and Ethnic Justice (GREJ) - Reports and Publications, 2009-2018; 6; 0.95 Cubic Feet
  - The Women's Media Center (121128) - Unspinning the Spin: The Women's Media Center Guide to Fair and Accurate Language, 2014 (Box 67, Folder 367)
  - Women's Learning Partnership (108396) - Leading to Action: A Political Participation Handbook for Women, 2010 (Box 67, Folder 368)
  - African American Policy Forum (125129) - Say Her Name: An Update on Resisting Police Brutality Against Black Women, 2015 July (Box 67, Folder 369)
  - Association for Women's Rights in Development (AWID) (117245): The Impact of the Crises on Women: Main Trends Across Regions, 2009 (Box 67, Folder 370)
  - Association for Women's Rights in Development (AWID) (117245) - Publications, 2010-2011; CD-R (Box 67)
  - Rutgers University Center for Women's Global Leadership (111417) - Maximum Available Resources and Human Rights, Analytical Report by Radhika Balakrishnan, Diane Elson, James Heintz, Nicholas Lusiani, 2011 (Box 67, Folder 371)
  - Institute for Women's Policy Research (118015) - The Status of Women in North Carolina, Cynthia Hess, Ariane Hegewisch, Youngmin Yi, and Claudia Williams, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 372)
  - Center for American Progress (119130) - The Shriver Report: A Woman's Nation Changes Everything, Edited by Heather Boushey and Ann O'Leary, 2009 (Box 67, Folder 373)
  - Women's Learning Partnership (108396) - Measuring Change: Monitoring and Evaluating Leadership Programs: A Guide for Organizations, 2010 (Box 68, Folder 378)
  - Legal Momentum: The Women's Legal Defense and Education Fund (117236) - Worst Off - Single-Parent Families in the United States, Timothy Casey and Laurie Maldonado, 2012 December (Box 68, Folder 379)
  - Rutgers University Center for Women's Global Leadership (111417) - The Year in Review, 2010 (Box 68, Folder 380)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center for Scholars (01351082) - The Women in Public Service Project, 2012-2014 (Box 68, Folder 381)
  - Regions Refocus (01401664) - Regions Refocus 2015: Fostering Regional and Feminist Solidarities for Justice: A Report on Nine Regional Workshops Between Policy-makers and Civil Society (Box 68, Folder 382)
  - The National Coalition on Black Civic Participation, Black Women's Roundtable 2016-2018 Strategic Plan (Box 68, Folder 383)
  - Women's Economic, Social and Political Action Network (WESPAN) (01451717) - From Participation to Power: Scaling Women's Collective Impact on Systemic Social Change, 2015 December (Box 68, Folder 384)
  - National Council for Research on Women (10800786) Women in Fund Management: A Road Map for Achieving Critical Mass - and Why It Matters, 2009 (Box 68, Folder 385)
  - Association for Women's Rights in Development (AWID) (11001258) - Toward a Future Without Fundamentalism: Analyzing Religious Fundamentalist Strategies and Feminist Responses, Cassandra Balchin, 2011 (Box 68, Folder 386)
  - Human Rights Watch (117221) - Rights Out of Reach: Obstacles to Health, Justice, and Protection for Displaced Victims of Gender-Based Violence in Colombia, 2012 (Box 68, Folder 387)
  - Human Rights Watch (117221) - The Law Was Against Me: Migrant Women's Access to Protection for Family Violence in Belgium, 2012 (Box 68, Folder 388)
  - Women's Learning Partnership (01400911) - Iranian Women's One Million Signatures: Campaign for Equality: The Inside Story, Noushin Ahmadi Khorasani, 2009 (Box 68, Folder 389)
  - Women's Media Center (01400913) - The Status of Women in the U.S. Media, 2014 (Box 68, Folder 390)
  - Women's Learning Partnership (10101227-4) - Leading to Action: A Political Participation Handbook for Women, 2010 (Box 68, Folder 391)
  - Women's Media Center (01301015) - Status of Women in the U.S. Media in 2013, Diana Mitsu Klos (Box 69, Folder 392)
  - International Association for Feminist Economics (11001259) - Feminist Economics, Volume Twenty, Number One, 2014 January (Box 69, Folder 393)
  - Women's Leadership Partnership (115016) Because Our Cause is Just (Grant-funded/Related Materials Submission Form only), 2013 (Box 69, Folder 394)
    A documentary about the struggle of women in countries who experienced the "Arab Spring"
  - Women's Learning Partnership (115016) - Leading to Choices: A Multimedia Curriculum for Leadership Learning (Grant-funded/Related Materials Submission Form only), 2011 (Box 69, Folder 395)
  - Women's Learning Partnership (115016) - Leading to Choices: A Multimedia Curriculum for Leadership Learning - 1, 2011; CD (Box 69)
  - Women's Learning Partnership (115016) - Leading to Choices: A Multimedia Curriculum for Leadership Learning - 2, 2011; CD (Box 69)
- A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) Prepared for Ford Foundation December 1971, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1971-1972; 7; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1971 December (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc. Volume II, 1972 February (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Atlanta Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Boston Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Chicago Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Cincinnati Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Houston Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Los Angeles Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Minneapolis Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the New York Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 13, Folder 102)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Philadelphia Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the San Francisco Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 13, Folder 104)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Seattle Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 13, Folder 105)
  - A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) in the Washington, D.C. Area Prepared for Ford Foundation, Eric Marder Associates, Inc., 1972 July (Box 13, Folder 106)
- Peace and Social Justice (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS) - Publications from Grantees and Researchers, 1997-2018; 8; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - Workshop on Labor and Social Justice in the Global Economy, Readings Part 2, 1997 April 25-27 (Box 33, Folder 184)
    University of Wisconsin-Madision, Sponsored by the Global Studies Program and the International Institute, University of Wisconsin-Madision
    Co-Conveners: Gay Seidman, David Trubek and Jonathan Zeitlin, University of Wisconsin-Madison
  - Jos Mart Desde La Visin de Anna Hyatt Huntington, Oficina del Historiador de la Ciudad de la Habana, 2018 (Box 33, Folder 185)
    Ford Foundation provided $500,000 towards Jos Mart statue project
    Restricted - Grant records - Open in 2028
  - Intaj al lamawawa fi tantheem al alradi al lubnaniya (The Production of Inequality in Master Planning in Lebanon) [Arabic], 2018 (Box 33, Folder 186)
    Grant number 128263; Middle East and North Africa (MENA) office
    Tabloid format collection of legal analysis, research and maps on the impact of masterplanning on inquality in 15 towns and villages in Lebanon
    Restricted - Grant material - Open in 2028
  - The Sweatshop Quandary: Corporate Responsibility on the Global Frontier, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 187-188)
  - Planning [in]Justice: Spatial Analysis for Urban Cairo, TADAMUN: The Cairo Urban Solidarity Initiative, 2018 (Box 33, Folder 189)
    Grantee: American University
    Grant Number: 127516
    Ford Office: Middle East and Northern Africa (MENA)
    Restricted - Grant Materials - Open in 2028
  - Global Labor Standards and the Apparel Industry: Can We Regulate Global Production?, Harvard University, Harvard Trade Union Program with Support from the Ford Foundation, 1998 October (Box 33, Folder 190)